The first need is my Stand.
My Stand, The World,
and what lies beyond it are
the path for men to advance further.
My second need is a trustworthy friend.
He must be someone
who can control his desires.
The desire for power, fame, money, sex…
He must be free of those things.
It must be someone who chooses
God's laws over the laws of men.
Will I, Dio, ever meet
someone with this character trait?
I also need
at least 36 souls of the worst convicts.
Souls of sinners have tremendous energy.
I need 14 words.
To prevent ever forgetting these words,
I will etch them onto my Stand itself.
I also need courage.
I must have the courage to
let go of my Stand just once.
My decaying Stand
will gather and absorb
the souls of 36 convicts.
It will then give birth to something new.
The spawned creature will awaken.
It will be curious about the 14 words
spoken by the trusted friend.
My friend will find me trustworthy
and he will consider me his friend.
Finally, I need the location.
It will be north latitude,
28 degrees 24 minutes,
west longitude, 80 degrees 36 minutes.
Wait for the next new moon.
Heaven will appear then.
Good morning, Father.
You've grown your hair out.
When was the last time
you returned home to the mainland?
I have no use for this place now.
The birthed creature now belongs to me.
The only thing left to do is
to wait for the time of heaven.
EPISODE 23: LOCK OF THE JAIL!
DISCIPLINARY WING
This is the worst!
How do I get out of this one?
This is the highest
maximum security measure ever.
All the guards have guns too.
It's too dangerous to be here
with all the guards,
even for just another minute.
Hey, Jolyne, can you hear me?
Are you listening?
The priest isn't on this island anymore.
He already left Green Dolphin Street.
He didn't take anything, though.
He wasn't carrying a baby with him!
It's too boring in here.
I even pierced my own belly button.
Do you have my father's disc, Emporio?
You got it now?
Did you get in contact
with the Speedwagon Foundation?
I can't. The security is too tight
right now.
I have the disc though, Jolyne.
I wouldn't put it down. Never.
Good. Well, I'm getting out of here.
- Lead the way.
- Jolyne.
The prison workers think
that you are the sole survivor from
the Disciplinary Wing.
Though they can't pin it on you,
you are the only person
they can question right now.
That's why this cell is
under strict observation.
Do you want to leave the cell
and come to my room?
No, Emporio.
By leave, I mean
getting out of this shitty prison.
I don't have any more time to waste.
I'm breaking out
of the Green Dolphin Island.
Show me the fastest way out of here.
I promise I'll contact
the Speedwagon Foundation.
I'll even do that today.
Wrong again, Emporio.
This problem is much bigger than
retrieving my father's disc now.
If F.F. were alive, they would be
going after that priest as we speak.
And now that I read my father's memory,
I understand what Pucchi meant
by 20 years.
I now understand why my father
had to seal Dio's ability.
My father would never let
the priest get away.
And I am Jolyne Cujoh!
I have to seal what he has obtained again!
Emporio.
Do you plan to stay here
for the rest of your life?
It's up to you,
but I want you to come with me.
You don't understand, Jolyne.
You don't get it at all.
But I do.
I can break out of these bars
in three minutes.
But what about after that?
No one is left to help you.
Ermes, Anastasia…
They are still under treatment
at the medical wing.
For some reason, Weather Forecast
has been holed up in his own room.
He won't even come visit my room.
I can leave through
the Ultra Security House Unit.
We got to the wetlands.
We can't.
No jailbreak attempt has ever succeeded.
Some prisoners were detained
for even contemplating a breakout.
Anyway, unless you can stop time
like your father,
no one can ever leave this prison.
I don't know what,
but there's something about this place.
Something more than surveillance cameras,
as if the prison itself was
a guard with a mind of its own.
Emporio, when is the next new moon?
Jolyne,
please, just wait for
the Speedwagon Foundation.
If we risk it, we might even
lose this disc we finally retrieved!
North latitude, 28 degrees 24 minutes.
West longitude, 80 degrees 36 minutes.
Where is that?
J-Jolyne…
I can't help you with this.
I have a message from Pale Snake.
Everything is over.
Don't try to leave this prison.
If you stay here, we won't get in the way
of you delivering the disc to Jotaro.
You've got guts, I'll give you that.
You showed me your face and your Stand.
And what's your name?
I am Mew Mew.
My Stand is called Jailhouse Lock.
I'm showing it to you as a warning.
Did he order you to finish me off?
If your plans are to break out
of this jail, then yes.
My plans?
No, I don't have any plans.
I'm leaving now!
Her Stand is in the bars!
I'll say it one more time, Jolyne Cujoh.
Don't touch the bars.
The more you think about escaping,
the closer you'll be to your death.
So this is what your ability does.
Take this!
What?
Do you need me to get someone?
Are you okay, Jolyne?
Where am I? Why am I here?
It's you, Gwess.
Am I in the female wing?
It hurts!
"One, grab a pen as soon as you can."
"Two, you can only retain up to
three new pieces of information."
"Three, defeat the User."
"Her name is Mew Mew."
What are these writings
and who wrote them?
Did someone write these
while I was asleep?
4. GO SEE EMPORIO
Oh, that's right.
I was locked up because of what happened
at the Ultra Security House Unit.
I gave myself a belly piercing.
Then, I ran into Emporio.
I told him I'm getting out of here
to go after the priest.
And then, after that…
After that…
I…
What?
After I said I was leaving,
I remember someone coming.
But who was it?
This is my handwriting. Did I write these?
No way. When did I write them, though?
I don't even remember writing them.
Tell me, why am I back here
in the female wing?
Hey! Answer me!
Why are you ignoring me?
I must've been sleeping
since I don't remember.
I'm serious!
Oh, also, do you have a pen?
I need a pen. Give me one.
Hey, you…
I'm really serious.
Do you think I wrote these on myself?
That I wrote on my own body?
2. YOU CAN ONLY RETAIN UP TO
THREE NEW PIECES OF INFORMATION
Hey, Gwess… be honest.
Have I been asking you the same question
over and over again?
Can you do me a favor?
Can you tell me
all the things I've asked you already?
"Jolyne, the prison doctor
has diagnosed you
with temporary amnesia brought on
by a great shock you received
while in the Hole."
"You can only memorize
up to three things at a time."
"You can still remember the past,
but if you memorize a fourth new thing,
you will forget one."
"However, since this will not affect
your life as a prisoner,
you were sent back
to the female wing two days ago."
Two days?
I've been here that long?
Get better soon, Jolyne.
For two days…
Have I been repeating the same questions
for two whole days?
But why?
"Defeat the User."
"Her name is Mew Mew."
This is…
Could this be… No, it can't be…
It's a Stand ability!
They're trying to keep me
locked up in here!
I'm under attack!
I remember seeing Emporio.
And then…
After that…
Let's see… I remember something happening.
WASH YOUR HANDS
DON'T FORGET TO WEAR YOUR PANTIES
Shit!
What the hell?
By the way, Gwess,
do you know anyone named Mew Mew?
You haven't asked that yet, Jolyne.
Her prisoner cell is upstairs.
I think she has ratty, blond hair.
She's about your height.
I don't know why she's here,
but I bet she was whoring around.
Where do I go to see her?
She was here until a moment ago, Jolyne.
She just walked by.
Can you tell me how she looks like again?
She's about 175cm.
Her hair is platinum blonde
and it's ratty.
She wears fishnets.
This is the female wing.
How did I get back here?
Who's Mew Mew?
What's the matter?
No…
You just said you wanted lunch.
It's almost lunchtime.
Is that right?
Don't think about getting out of here,
Jolyne Cujoh.
You can't attack me
and my Jailhouse Lock, ever.
STAND NAME: STONE OCEAN
STAND MASTER: JOLYNE CUJOH
Pale Snake was the priest.
F.F. figured it out for us.
And then….
They died, didn't they?
Bottoms up.
I'll avenge you.
Hey! Why are you grabbing food?
Give me your ticket first.
I'm here to grab the packed lunch.
Like I said, ticket first.
You won't be sneaking one away.
Now show it to me. Stop taking forever.
If you don't have it, then leave.
Now scram.
Next.
Did I leave it next to my bed?
I've got to write it somewhere
so I don't forget it.
LEAVE FOOD TICKET IN HERE
What?
Why am I here again?
Oh, why did I come back up here?
I can't remember a thing.
Why did I come back up here?
Hey Jolyne, that's my lunch!
You ate a good bit of it!
You ate my favorite cheese penne!
You left your ticket
in your pocket, remember?
Sorry.
I'll get you another one with my ticket.
No, it's fine. Just stop.
I can get it, just give me your ticket.
Can you write it down somewhere
that I have your ticket?
Oh, sorry.
I GAVE MY FOOD TICKET TO GWESS
What's this, a User?
Is it referring to a Stand?
Oh, that's right.
I have to go see Emporio.
I tried to break out
of the confinement cell.
Emporio must have been with me then.
Emporio might know something.
And I need to get out of here.
I GAVE MY FOOD TICKET TO GWESS
Hey, I said the mustard's out!
There's not a squeeze left in here.
Do you have another bottle?
Why does it feel like
I'm always eating the same food?
I don't have an appetite.
I'll just eat the cheese penne.
Can I sit with you, Jolyne?
I'm sitting down here.
I stepped on a cockroach earlier.
It was so gross.
Who is she? She seems to know me.
Blonde…
Ratty hair…
Fishnet tights.
What the hell did you do that for?
Do you want mustard?
What about ketchup?
You aren't fond of dressing, are you?
It's pretty good.
Thanks.
By the way, what's your name?
Oh, no.
I'm so sorry,
I spilled it on you! Let's get you clean.
Your arm got drenched.
We need to go clean it off.
Take that jacket off.
2. YOU CAN ONLY RETAIN UP TO
THREE NEW PIECES OF INFORMATION
Oh, that's so much better.
There, all squeaky clean!
Let's check your pocket too.
That's a gift from me.
Jailhouse Lock.
Anyone who touches the cell bars
with my Stand in it to try and escape
can then only remember
three pieces of information.
Their life is then restricted
by the three memories.
It's worse than not having
any memories at all.
They experience over and over again
that everything they do is meaningless.
Eventually, this cycle of failure
becomes etched in their bodies.
They then lose all drive to escape.
You can even say that they are crippled.
This is what you get
for trying to break out.
What do I need to do?
What's important to me?
What shouldn't I forget?
That's all I need to get out of this trap.
I just need one thing!
I need to recall it now.
If I don't recall it right this minute,
I'll forget it forever!
Just one thing!
What matters to me?
GO SEE EMPORIO
This is all I need.
I'll leave one memory open.
These two things.
These two things are all I need.
The rest, I don't need.
I need to leave this place!
I spilled… my water.
I need to… unplug the power.
The power is shorting out.
Or else, I can't leave out of
that exit to go see Jolyne.
I have things I need to tell Jolyne!
I can't forget them!
I have to leave this room!
I spilled my water.
MEMORY ONE: I SPILLED MY WATER
I need to… unplug the power.
MEMORY TWO: I NEED TO UNPLUG THE POWER
The power is shorting out.
MEMORY THREE: THE POWER IS SHORTING
Or else, I can't leave out of that exit…
MEMORY FOUR: OR ELSE, I CAN'T LEAVE
THIS ROOM TO GO SEE JOLYNE
MEMORY THREE
…to go see Jolyne.
Wait a second.
"Go see Emporio"?
I'm sure I read that name on her arm.
I need to go make sure.
No one can escape this place.
GO SEE EMPORIO
Subtitle translation by: Megumi Hunter